Problem A
An integer N is input.
Output 1 and 0 alternately, with 1 being output N+1 times and 0 being output N times.
Maybe it's easier to just write 10 N times and then add a 1?
In C++ or something, you'd probably end up writing a loop.
The code is also in the "Explanation" section, so feel free to check it out.
Problem B
There are coins from N countries, each in some amount.
You can exchange some number of coins from country 1 for some number of coins from country 2.
This can be done any number of times.
The same applies to countries 2 and 3.
If N were larger, the same would apply to countries 3 and 4, and so on.
What is the maximum number of coins you can get from country N?
N can be up to 200,000, just so you know.
There won't be an excessive increase in the number of coins.
First, divide to see how many times you can exchange from 1 to 2,
actually make that number of exchanges,
then repeat from 2 to 3...
The order of multiplication and division is quite important in programming, huh?
Because you can't exchange half a time in this case.
Problem C
There's a 2D field made of land and sea.
Taro starts from a square
and makes a certain pattern of moves.
It's unknown from which square he started, but
it's known that he didn't fall into the sea during the process.
How many squares could he possibly be on now?
The field is at most 500×500, and the number of moves is at most 500.
By the way, the outer perimeter is all sea, which might make things a bit easier.
Try all starting squares...
Wouldn't that work?
500 cubed is 125 million,
which might or might not be feasible depending on the language,
and there's no easy way to improve it, so we have to go with that.
What if it doesn't fit in time?
Have ChatGPT translate it into C++ for you.
Problem D
We're interested in things such as
"integers that are exactly divisible by either 4 or 6, but not both."
So 12, which is divisible by both 4 and 6, is excluded.
Find the fifth smallest number in this list.
...That's just an example, the actual numbers will be much larger.
Pinpointing the answer might be difficult,
but asking "Is the answer less than or equal to 20?" isn't too hard.
It's the same as asking "Are there more than 5 numbers less than or equal to 20 in the list?"
A classic example where starting with binary search makes things clearer.
So we just need to count the numbers less than or equal to 20 in the list,
count multiples of 4 and 6,
and subtract multiples of 12 twice.
In C++, the least common multiple can be handled with a library.
Problem E
There's a sequence of 0s and 1s.
Follow two types of queries.
Query 1
Invert all values in a specific range.
Turn 0s into 1s, and 1s into 0s, right?
Query 2
Determine if 0s and 1s appear in perfect alternation within a specific range.
The length of the sequence and the number of queries are both up to 500,000.
Mark places where the same number appears consecutively.
Then, when flipping,
actually, nothing happens except at the ends.
To determine if it's alternating,
if there's not even one mark inside, it's OK.
If there's even one, it's not OK.
So, we can just put the number of marks into a segment tree.
A Binary Indexed Tree is also sufficient,
and since it's just about finding 1s, a balanced binary search tree like std::set would also work,
but with these constraints, using a balanced binary search tree in Python is like a dare.
By the way, the talk about marks corresponds to taking the difference mod 2.
Problem F
There's an undirected graph,
with a weight assigned to each vertex.
Additionally, there are several pieces on each vertex.
Choose one piece,
and select several vertices adjacent to the vertex where the piece is.
The total weight of the selected vertices
must be less than the weight of the vertex with the piece.
Then, remove the selected piece
and place one piece on each of the selected vertices.
How many times can this series of operations be repeated?
If there's nowhere to go after choosing a piece, the only option is to remove it, right?
Ah, yes.
The number of vertices and edges, and the weights are all up to 5000, and there are plenty of pieces.
It sounds complicated, but,
you said "less than," right?
So, the undirected graph thing is a lie,
it's a one-way street from larger to smaller.
It's a DAG, then.
So, we'll look in ascending order.
Since pieces don't interact with each other,
if we know how many operations can be done with one piece,
it's like solving a knapsack problem N times.
We didn't have time for Problem G, but I'll introduce a similar problem.
If you liked it, please subscribe to the channel.
Thank you for watching!